For the purposes of a report or to show
a scenario, one may want to show data
in a calculated form. Take, for example, this
query that shows some information on products,
including the product's list price. Say
we want to add a column that will show
the list price minus 10% as a
column titled 10% Off Price.
I will add a comma after the existing List Price
field and then add the ListPrice column again,
this time multiplying it by .9 to take 10% off
the price, and then I will add a column alias of
'10% Off Price' in quotes. I will execute this
statement, and we see that the query works.
However, on a second inspection of the pricing
column, it would be nice if the dollar amounts
looked like dollar amounts, carried to two places.
There are a few ways to format this number,
but the easiest way is to add the string
function (str) to this new, computed column.
I will add the letters str and an open
parenthesis before the column, then 8,
2, and close parenthesis to indicate
eight characters long with two numbers
after the decimal point. Let's see how this
looks when I execute it. It looks good.